<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hyper V on Samuel Debruyn</title>
    <link>http://staging.sa.muel.be/tags/hyper-v/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hyper V on Samuel Debruyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 22:38:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://staging.sa.muel.be/tags/hyper-v/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix common Hyper-V errors on Windows 10</title>
      <link>http://staging.sa.muel.be/2015/how-to-fix-common-hyper-v-errors-on-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 22:38:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://staging.sa.muel.be/2015/how-to-fix-common-hyper-v-errors-on-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short post is more of a note to myself for when I run into the same problem. I just wasted an hour on it so I guess that justifies it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happened? I wanted to check out the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/machine/&#34;&gt;Docker Machine&lt;/a&gt; with Hyper-V support, but the Hyper-V Manager told me it could not connect to my local computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I opened Hyper-V Manager all I saw was an introduction. I then clicked &lt;em&gt;Connect to server&lt;/em&gt; and selected my local computer. A confusing error message appeared telling me that an object was not found. It was the &lt;em&gt;Hyper-V Virtual Machine Management service&lt;/em&gt; which seemed to be missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hypervisor was running, the mentioned service was running, there were no errors in the Event Viewer&amp;hellip; everything seemed to be working fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of Googling led me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.spiceworks.com/how_to/122307-fix-error-managing-hyper-v-server-2012-r2-from-windows-10&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; mentioning a command that fixed this problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MOFCOMP %SYSTEMROOT%\System32\WindowsVirtualization.V2.mof
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command reinitializes Hyper-V management on your computer and fixes this error. It seems to be a frequent cause of headaches on Windows 10 hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>